https://www.printcartridgedirect.com/privacy.php?osCsid=300e5ppmf4mjsiq29639cpdm34

Toggle Navigation
TonerAppleBrotherCanonDellEpsonHPIBMKyoceraLexmarkMinoltaMuratecOkiPanasonicPantumPhilipsQMSRicohSamsungSharpTallyGenicomToshibaXeroxInkjetAdvent InkApple InkBrother InkBT InkCanon InkCompaq InkDell InkEpson InkFrancotyp InkHP InkKodak InkLexmark InkNeopost InkOlivetti InkPhilips InkPitney Bowes InkRicoh InkSamsung InkSharp InkXerox InkHardwarePrintersMedia StorageBlu Ray MediaCD MediaDVD MediaUSB StorageRibbon & RollsBrotherCitizenEpsonFrancotypIBMLexmarkMitsubishiNewburyOkiPanasonicPhilipsPrintronixSagemSharpStarTallyGenicomXeroxZebraTechnologyPaperGloss Photo PaperGreeting CardsMatt Photo PaperPlain PaperT-Shirt Transfers
PRIVACY POLICY
In this privacy policy references to “we”, “us” and “our” are to PrintCartridgeDirect.com. References to “our website” or “the website” are to www.printcartridgedirect.com. This privacy notice provides you with the necessary information regarding your rights and our obligations, plus explains how, why and when we process your personal data.
The information we collect
Printcartridgedirect processes your personal information to meet our legal, statutory and contractual obligations and to provide you with our products and services. We will never collect any unnecessary personal data from you and do not process your information in any way, other than as specified in this notice.
The personal data that we collect is:
Name
Address
Email
Telephone
We collect information using website orders and online forms.
How we use your personal data
We take your privacy very seriously and will never disclose, share or sell your data without your consent; unless required to do so by law. We only retain your data for as long as is necessary and for the purposes specified in this notice. Where you have consented to us providing you with promotional offers and marketing, you are free to withdraw this consent at any time. The purposes and reasons for processing your personal data are detailed below:
We collect your personal data in the performance of a contract or to provide a service and to ensure that orders are completed and can be sent out to your preferred address
We will occasionally send you marketing information where we have assessed that it is beneficial to you as a customer and in our interests. Such information will be non-intrusive and is processed on the grounds of legitimate interests
Your rights
You have the right to access any personal information that we process about you and to request information about:
What personal data we hold about you
The purposes of the processing
The categories of personal data concerned
The recipients to whom the personal data has/will be disclosed
How long we intend to store your personal data for
If we did not collect the data directly from you, information about the source
If you believe that we hold any incomplete or inaccurate data about you, you have the right to ask us to correct and/or complete the information and we will strive to do so as quickly as possible; unless there is a valid reason for not doing so, at which point you will be notified.
You also have the right to request erasure of your personal data or to restrict processing (where applicable) in accordance with the data protection laws; as well as to object to any direct marketing from us. Where applicable, you have the right to data portability of your information and the right to be informed about any automated decision-making we may use.
If we receive a request from you to exercise any of the above rights, we may ask you to verify your identity before acting on the request; this is to ensure that your data is protected and kept secure.
Who we may share your personal data with
In order to complete your order we may need to share some of your personal information with some fulfilment partners and couriers. We do not share or disclose any of your personal information without your consent, other than for the purposes specified in this notice or where there is a legal requirement. All processors acting on our behalf only process your data in accordance with instructions from us and comply fully with this privacy policy, the data protection laws and any other appropriate confidentiality and security measures.
Safeguarding measures
We take your privacy seriously and take every reasonable measure and precaution to protect and secure your personal data. We work hard to protect you and your information from unauthorised access, alteration, disclosure or destruction and have several layers of security measures in place, including, but not limited to:
SSL encryption
Restricted access
IT authentication
Firewalls
Anti-virus/malware
Consequences of not providing your data
You are not obligated to provide your personal information to us, however, as this information is required for us to provide you with our services, deliver your products and for other Legitimate Interests, we will not be able to offer all of our services without it.
How long is your data kept?
We only ever retain personal information for as long as is necessary and we have strict review and retention policies in place to meet these obligations. We are required under UK tax law to keep your basic personal data (name, address, contact details) for a minimum of 6 years after which time it will be destroyed.
Where you have consented to us using your details for direct marketing, we will keep such data until you notify us otherwise and/or withdraw your consent.
Making a complaint
We only process your personal information in compliance with this privacy policy and in accordance with the relevant data protection laws. If, however you wish to raise a complaint regarding the processing of your personal data or are unsatisfied with how we have handled your information, you have the right to lodge a complaint with the Information Commissioner's Office who are the supervisory authority. Click here to contact the Information Commissioner's Office.
Cookies
What is a cookie?
A 'cookie' is a small piece of data sent from a website and stored on the user's computer by the user's web browser while the user is browsing. When you visit a site that uses cookies for the first time, a cookie is downloaded onto your computer or mobile device so that the next time you visit that site, your device will remember useful information such as items added in the shopping cart, visited pages or logging in options.
Why we use cookies
When you visit a site that uses cookies for the first time, a cookie is downloaded onto your computer or mobile device so that the next time you visit that site, your device will remember useful information such as items added in the shopping cart, visited pages or logging in options.
Cookies are widely used in order to make websites work, or to work more efficiently, and our site relies on cookies to optimise user experience and for features and services to function properly.
Cookie Control
Most web browsers allow some control to restrict or block cookies through the browser settings, however if you disable cookies you may find this affects your ability to use certain parts of our website or services. For more information about cookies visit https://www.aboutcookies.org.
Other websites
Our website may contain links to other websites. This privacy policy only applies to this website so when you link to other websites you should read their own privacy policies.
Continue
